Søren Bruus Frank

Software Developer - Technology Designer



Contact

Strandparken 1, 1. th. 8000 Aarhus C Denmark +45 61 26 19 13 soerenbf@gmail.com

http://www.sorenbf.dk fb://sorenbf linkedin://soerenbf

Languages

Danish mother tongue
English fluently
German basic
Swedish conversaional

Programming

✓ Java
 ✓ Javascript
 HTML5/CSS3
 AngularJS
 jQuery
 Obj-C
 Swift
 iOS
 Git

Interests

Technology
Programming
Graphical Design
Video Games
Travelling
Watersports
Wintersports
Health and Fitness

Personal statement

As a recent graduate from the master's degree of IT Product Development at Aarhus University I excel specifically within the areas of software development and design/development processes. I love designing and developing software and embedded software solutions while incorporating users and stakeholders in the process. I believe and know from experience that the outcome of a design process will almost never be as initially envisioned, and as such the entire process must be agile to accommodate the changing world of information technology.

Education

2013–2016 Masters: IT Product Development

Aarhus University, Aarhus

Project oriented education with a focus on programming, product development/design, and business and innovation including both scientific and practical work with the process of designing and developing IT products and technolo-

gies.

2010–2013 **Bachelor:** IT Product Development

Aarhus University, Aarhus

2010–2010 **Snowboarding programme**

Oure Sports Academy, Oure

2005–2008 **STX:** Gymnasium (natural sciences)

Skanderborg Gymnasium, Skanderborg

Math (A), Physics (A), Chemistry (A), English (B), German (B)

1995–2005 **Elementary school**

Skanderborg Realskole, Skanderborg

Thesis project

Feb. 2016 Voice Control for Interactive Audible News in the Home

Stibo A/S, Aarhus

In collaboration with research partners Archant Media Group (based in Norwich, England) and Cxense (based in Oslo, Norway) we developed an application prototype for Amazon Echo through an iterative design process incorporating both users and stakeholders of news consumption and production to explore the possibilities and limitations offered in voice user interfaces with acoustic output for the news industry.

Experience

2011–2015 Aarhus University IT Support

Aarhus, Denmark

IT Helpdesk Supporter

During my studies at Aarhus University, I was employed at the IT department of the university administration and the arts faculty.

Responsibilities:

- Auditorium and meeting room equipment maintenance and support
- Task delegation and fixing smartphones, computers, and printers
- IT support for both students and staff by e-mail, telephone, and physical support both in helpdesk and on location

Partner and Developer

Started the company with my twin brother during my studies when I had acquired the necessary skills to do so. We worked with iOS application development as white label work for other companies. The lifetime of the company spanned from May 2012 to November 2012, at which point we put it on hold due to work pressure from the side of the university.

Responsibilities:

- Development of iOS applications following a photoshop design template
- Communication with client company

Miscellaneous

2008-2009	Personalekontoret	Skanderborg, Denmark
	Substitute worker	
2007-2008	Post Danmark	Skanderborg, Denmark
	Weekend mail carrier	
2004-2007	Kafé K	Skanderborg, Denmark
	Kitchen Assistant	

Skills

Methods

Business models, Agile development methodologies, Software design patterns, Workshops, Field studies, Design processes

Software development

Object oriented programming, Relational databases, Git, Mobile Development, Front-end, Back-end, Version control

Programming languages: Java, Obj-C, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Swift, XML, XSLT, Typescript, LESS, C, SQL

Frameworks: AngularJS, jQuery, Node.js, MySQL, Arduino, Unity3D, Android, Parse, Oculus Rift, Leap Motion, UlKit (iOS), JSP, Java servlets

Computer applications

Programming environments: Atom, Eclipse, Xcode Text editing: Microsoft Word, Pages, LaTeX Data analysis: Microsoft Excel, Numbers Presentation: Microsoft PowerPoint, Keynote

Other: Terminal (unix), Git